Register of the Edward Geary Lansdale papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Office Files from the Philippines (II), 1950-1954 (Box 34)
  - Villiors, Geoffrey S., "The Philippines Election,", 1953 November 20
- Office Files from Vietnam, 1953-1956 (Box 35)
  Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, and papers from Lansdale's initial period in Vietnam (1954 to 1956), including schedules and notes from his visit to Vietnam as a member of General John W. O'Daniel's mission to the French forces (1953), arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Miscellany (Box 35)
  - Bohannan, Charles T. R., recommendation for promotion, 1955 May 16
  - Cholon, undated
  - Clark, Lt. General Bruce C., visit to MAAG-Vietnam, 1955 September 12
  - Clippings, Philippine newspapers, 1955
  - Correspondence
    - General
    - Miscellany
    - Unidentified
    - Buckens, F., undated
    - Cabell, C. P., 1956
    - Collins, J. Lawton, 1955
    - Conein, Lucien E., 1956
    - Fishel, Wesley R., 1955
    - Godel, William H., 1956
    - Hugo, Lt., 1955
    - James, Daniel V., 1955-56
    - Jones, Robert H., Jr., 1955
    - Lacy, William, 1954
    - Lindley, Ernest K., 1955
    - Magsaysay, Ramon, 1955-1956
    - Mankiewicz, Joseph, 1956
    - Melvin, George, 1956
    - O'Daniel, General John W., 1953
    - Phillips, Rufus, undated
    - Sinclair, T. L., 1956
    - Valeriano, Napolian and Emma, 1955-1956
    - Wertz, Colonel, 1955
    - Wilkins, Ford, 1955
    - Yepez, Ceferina, 1955
  - Godel, William H., visit, 1956 January
  - MATS document, with memorandum and letter, 1954
  - Memoranda, undated, 1953-1956
  - Messages, undated
  - Monthly reports, Lansdale, undated
  - Notes
    - (1), undated
    - (2), undated
    - 1954 September 27
    - Staff meeting, 1955 December 5
  - O'Daniel, General John W., mission to French forces in Vietnam, 1953
  - Operation Brotherhood, undated
  - Reports
    - Army-Navy-Air Force, undated
    - Guerrilla warfare, with attached notes by General O'Daniel, undated
    - Pacification, with annex, undated
    - Warfare, undated
    - Warfare, with attached memorandum to General O'Daniel, 1953 June 25
- Office Files from the United States Department of Defense, Office of the Secretary of Defense, 1957-1964
  Office files from Lansdale's years as Deputy Assistant Secretary and Assistant Secretary of Defense for special operations, including correspondence, memoranda, speeches, subject files, and materials collected as a staff member of the President's Committee on Military Assistance (Draper Committee), arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General (Box 36)
  - Miscellany
  - Correspondence
    - General
    - Miscellany
    - Miscellany, material withheld pending declassification review
    - Unidentified
    - Abrignani, Lt. Colonel A., 1962
    - Abueva, Jose V., 1962
    - Adevoso, Terry, 1960
    - Alabaster, Captain Harold L., 1963
    - Alden, Colonel Victor W., 1962-1963
    - Alvarado, Lorenzo, 1958, 1960-1961, 1963
    - Anderson, Dillon, 1959, 1963
    - Anderson, Admiral George W., 1961
    - Anspacher, John M., 1963
    - Anthis, Brig. General Rollen H., 1963
    - Arellano, Oscar J., 1958, 1961-1963
    - Arundel, Arthur W., 1963-1964
    - Atkinson, Stan, 1962-1963
    - Ayala Mercado, Brig. General Jaime, 1963
    - Baclogan, Uldarico S., 1961
    - Baker, Major Joseph, 1959
    - Banzon, Colonel Joseph, 1958, 1961-1962
    - Baratt, Colonel Thomas H., 1960-1961
    - Barber, Willard F., 1965
    - Belen, Frederick C., 1963
    - Bashore, Major Boyd T., 1962-1963
    - Belmonte, Cherie Palileo, 1962
    - Benjamin, James, 1958
    - Berle, A. A., Jr., 1963
    - Berle, Peter A., 1963
    - Bernido, Governor, 1960
    - Bingham, Colonel Sidney V., 1961
    - Black, Colonel Edward F., 1958, 1961-1963
    - Blackburn, Mrs. D. D., 1962
    - Bleiman, Major Junius Jay, 1961
    - Bohannan, Colonel Charles T. R., 1963
    - Bohlen, Charles E., 1959
    - Boonstra, Clarence A., 1963
    - Borg, Parker W., 1965
    - Borromeo, Colonel Emilio O., 1959, 1963
    - Bowell, Captain John H., 1963
    - Boyce, Major R. O., 1963
    - Brand, Robert A., 1958
    - Brill, William H., 1963
    - Britton, Edward, 1963-1965
    - Brunn, Robert R., 1962 (Box 37)
    - Bullock, Major General W. C., 1960-1961
    - Burke, Admiral Arleigh, 1958, 1961-1964
    - Burns, Captain Robert J., 1961-1962
    - Bursk, Edward C., Jr., 1963
    - Busch, Noel, 1963
    - Bushner, R. H., 1962
    - Button, Colonel Robert E., 1963
    - Cabal, Manuel F., 1960
    - Cabauatan, Sylvia, 1963
    - Cabell, General C. P., 1962-1963
    - Campbell, Reverend David A., 1962
    - Cao, General Van Thanh [see: Van Thanh Cao, General]
    - Carino, Lt. Colonel Laureano G., 1960
    - Carroll, Lt. General Joseph F., 1961
    - Cassady, Major General Emmett B., 1960, 1963
    - Cerny, Karl H. [see also: Croker, Dickey, and Fall], 1965
    - Chang, Leo S., 1961
    - Chapman, John W., 1963
    - Chapelle, Dickey, 1961-1962
    - Chapman, Colonel John W., 1963
    - Chester, Esther and George, 1960
    - Chiang Ching-Kuo, General, 1963
    - Chuong, Mel, 1963
    - Chuong, Tran Van [see: Tran Van Chuong]
    - Claggett, Captain Bladen D., 1961
    - Clark, Colonel Sidney R., 1961
    - Close, William T., 1965
    - Cochran, Captain Drexel B., 1962
    - Combs, Major General Cecil E., 1963
    - Compton, Major General K. K., 1960, 1963
    - Comstock, Paul B., 1959, 1962
    - Conein, Lucien, 1959
    - Cook, Col. Truman F., 1963
    - Cooke, Captain Charles M., Jr., 1963
    - Cooke, Dwight, 1960-1961, 1964
    - Cowlen, Myron M., 1958-1960, 1962
    - Cox, Alfred T., 1964
    - Croker, Stephen B. [see also: Cerny, Dickey, and Fall], 1965
    - Crum, Lt. Colonel Leroy A., 1962-1963
    - Cruz, Lt. General Pelagio A., undated
    - Cuaderno, Governor M., Sr., 1959
    - Cumming, Hugh S., Jr., 1961, 1963
    - Curtin, Brig. General Richard D., 1963
    - Dang, Nguyen Phuoc [see: Nguyen Phuoc Dang]
    - Davis, Saville R., 1963
    - Delbeque, Leon, 1960
    - Del Mar, Roland H., 1963
    - De Marco, Michael, 1961
    - De Puy, Colonel W. E., 1963
    - Deutch, John M., 1960
    - Deutch, Michael J., 1957, 1960, 1963
    - Dickey, William P. [see also: Cerny, Croker, and Fall], 1965
    - Diem, President Ngo Dinh [see: Ngo Dinh Diem, President]
    - Dinh, Tran Van [see: Tran Van Dinh]
    - Donnelly, Major General H. C., 1963
    - Douglas, James H., 1961, 1963
    - Draper, Major General William H., 1963
    - Drew, John A., 1957
    - Dulles, Allen W., 1961
    - E. (unidentified), 1959
    - Ellis, John M., 1957
    - Emery, Ethan, 1961
    - Espino, Colonel Romeo, 1960, 1962
    - Evans, Robert F., 1958
    - Ezpeleta, Mariano, 1961
    - Fall, Bernard B. [see also: Cerny, Croker, and Dickey], 1965
    - Felt, Admiral Harry D., 1961-1962
    - Ferris, Sergeant Al, 1962
    - Fischer, John, 1965
    - Fishel, Wesley R., 1957, 1961-1963
    - Fraleigh, Bert, 1957, 1960, 1964
    - Frank, Rear Admiral (ret.) N. J., Jr., 1963
    - French, Jerome T., 1963
    - Galang, Ricardo C., 1963 (Box 38)
    - Galula, David, 1960, 1962-1963
    - Gaston, Ben, 1961
    - Gates, John M., Jr., 1960, 1962
    - Gates, Thomas S., 1961
    - Gleason, James P., 1965
    - Go Puan Seng, 1960-1962
    - Goffio, Frank L., 1963
    - Goldini, Lt. Colonel John E., 1963
    - Graham, William L., 1959
    - Grant, Lt. General Harold W., 1960, 1963
    - Gray, Brig. General Fred C., 1963
    - Griswold, Lt. General Francis H., 1963-1964
    - Guerrero-Nakpil, Carmen, 1961
    - Guerrero, Major Jose M., 1958
    - Guinn, Lt. Colonel Uinn, 1963
    - Jones, Colonel George, 1959
    - Haddad, Lester Marcel, 1961
    - Hadley, Arthur T., 1961-1962
    - Hagerty, James C., 1958
    - Haley, Don, 1958
    - Hall, Jes E., Jr., 1959
    - Halloran, Robert P., 1960
    - Hardin, Colonel Ernest C., 1963
    - Hardwick, Strother, 1963-1965
    - Harris, Lt. General Hunter, 1963
    - Haugerud, Howard E., 1962
    - Hauptli, Jule B., 1958, 1960
    - Herter, Christian A., Jr., 1963
    - Higgins, Ray, 1959
    - Hilbert, Philip F., 1963
    - Hill, John Calvin, Jr., 1963
    - Hilsman, Roger, 1963
    - Hoai, Le Khoc [see: Le Khoc Hoai]
    - Hobbs, Major General L. S., 1960
    - Hobson, O. L., 1961
    - Hodges, Sergeant Alfred E., 1963
    - Hoffman, Colonel A. A., 1962
    - Ilustre, Ernie, 1960
    - Irvine, C. S., 1960
    - Irwin, Jack, 1958
    - De Jaegher, Reverend Raymond J., undated
    - James, Daniel V., 1959-1963
    - Johnston, Lynwood, 1965
    - Jolly, Colonel, 1963
    - Jonas, Gilbert, 1962
    - Jones, George M., 1959-1961
    - Jones, Harry S., 1963
    - Jones, Helen E., 1958-1963
    - Jordan, Amos A., 1958-1961
    - Jorden, Bill, 1961
    - Judd, Walter, 1962
    - Jurado, Augusto, 1963
    - Justiniano, Major Medardo, 1960-1962
    - Karrick, Samuel N., 1960
    - Katzenback, Edward L., Jr., 1963
    - Kelly, Pat, 1958, 1960, 1962-1963, 1967
    - Kent, James R., 1965
    - Klocko, Richard P., 1963
    - Knight, Robert Huntington, 1964
    - Korsmeyer, F. B., 1963
    - L., A. F. (unidentified), 1958
    - Lahoney, William J., 1963
    - Laird, Melvin, 1963
    - Landon, Dr. Kenneth P., 1964
    - Lapus, Ismael D., 1962
    - Lauve, Anita C., 1961
    - Le Khac Hoai, 1960
    - Le Van Ty, 1963
    - Lederer, W. J., 1957
    - Ledesma, Oscar, 1964
    - Lee, J. M., 1960
    - Lemnitzer, L. L., 1963
    - Ligon, E. S., 1963
    - Lim, Roberto H., 1963
    - Lincoln, G. A., 1959-1962
    - Lindholm, Richard W., 1958
    - Litonjua, Anatolio, 1960
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1963
    - Logo, Pedro, 1961 (Box 39)
    - Love, Robert L., 1962
    - Lovett, Ralph B., 1961
    - Lowrance, V. L., 1963
    - Lukban, Jose G., 1960-1963
    - Lwin, Maung, 1960
    - Mabry, Brig. General George, 1963
    - Madlangbayan, Francisco, 1962
    - Magsaysay, Jesus, 1957
    - Magsaysay, Luz B., 1957
    - Mahon, James E., 1963
    - Mai Huu Xuan, 1962
    - Maing, 1958
    - Manahan, Manuel P., 1962
    - Manglapus, Raul S., 1960
    - Manhart, A. H., 1960
    - Marshall, S. L. A., 1963
    - Martin, Glen W., 1963
    - Matheson, Colonel S. H., 1961
    - Maynard, Leonard, 1958
    - McAlister, John T., 1963
    - McCarty, Chester E., 1963
    - McCormick, William M., 1963
    - McElroy, Francis, 1965
    - McGuire, Perkins, 1962
    - McHale, Thomas R., 1962
    - McLean, Don, 1961-1963
    - McMicking, J. R., 1960
    - Mecklin, John M., 1962-1963
    - Mellor, Charles Richard, 1958-1962
    - Melvin, George H., 1960
    - Meng, William J., 1963
    - Menzi, Colonel H. M., 1960
    - Mertz, Charles T., 1958-1963
    - Methvin, Gene, 1964
    - Miller, Ann, 1963
    - Miller, Henry L., 1959-1963
    - Miller, R. H., 1961
    - Mills, Leonard J., 1960
    - Milton, T. R., 1961-1963
    - Miniclair, Louis, 1962
    - Mitchell, William L., 1963
    - Montgomery, J. B., 1963
    - Moorman, Thomas S., 1961
    - Moseley, George V. H., 1958-1961
    - Murphy, Charles J. V., 1962-1963
    - Murray, W. E., 1964
    - Navarro, Edmundo, 1961-1963
    - Nazareno, Rodolfo, 1963
    - Neves, Conceicao da Costa, 1958-1962
    - Ngau, Trinh Hung [see: Trinh Hung Ngau]
    - Ngo Dinh Diem, President, 1957, 1960-1961
    - Nguyen Phuoc Dang, 1964
    - Nguyen Thai, 1961-1963
    - Nielsen, Waldemar A., 1960-1961
    - Nihart, F. B., 1960
    - Niveras, Charlie, 1963
    - Nolting, Frederick E., 1963
    - Norman, Lloyd, 1962-1963
    - Noshe, G., 1960
    - Nurnberg, Malcolm L., 1963
    - Nutt, Mrs. Howard N., 1964
    - O'Daniel, John W. ("Mike"), 1956-1964
    - O'Donnell, E. J., 1963
    - O'Donnell, Emmett, 1960-1963
    - Oka, Takashi [see also: SUBJECT FILE/Vietnam/Politics and government], 1965 (Box 40)
    - O'Malley, Edward A., 1963
    - O'Meara, Andrew P., 1963
    - O'Neal, the Hon. Emmet, 1963
    - Orendain, Juan C., 1958-1962
    - Orobia, Eustacio D., 1962
    - Osanka, Franklin Mark, 1963
    - Palileo, Cherle, undated
    - Parker, Theodore W., 1962
    - Patton, George S., 1963
    - Peabody, George, 1957, 1961
    - Pelzer, Karl J., 1964
    - Peralta, Macario, 1963
    - Phillips, Rufus
      - 1957-1963
      - 1963
    - Phillips, William, 1963
    - Pille, Pedro C., 1959
    - Pope, Edward J., 1963
    - Pritchard, Gilbert L., 1963
    - Purdom, Walt, 1961
    - Puyat, Gil J., 1960
    - RAND Corporation, 1962-63
    - Randall, Hal, 1961
    - Ravenholt, Albert, 1958-1960
    - Reed, John M., 1961
    - Rhine, Robert H., 1962-1963
    - Rhinehart, Jon, 1962
    - Richards, Peter C., 1961-1965
    - Riley, John F., 1963
    - Roces, Joaquin, 1961
    - Rockefeller, John, III, 1957
    - Roderick, Charles, 1963
    - Romulo, General Carlos P., 1962
    - Rosson, General William B., 1961-1962
    - Rostow, Walt W., 1961, 1963
    - Rowland, Robert R., 1963
    - Ruenheck, Wilbert H., 1962-1963
    - Russell, A. Lewis, 1963
    - Samford, John A., 1960, 1963
    - San Juan, Frisco F., 1964
    - Sananikone, Oudone, 1963
    - Sanjines, Julio, 1963
    - Santos, Alejo S., 1961
    - Schanche, Don A., 1962
    - Seng, Go Puan [see: Go Puan Seng]
    - Sese, Alfredo C., 1960
    - Shaplen, Robert, 1962
    - Sheldon, Kenneth P., 1961-1962
    - Sheppard, David, 1964
    - Sherman, Adrian F., 1962-1963
    - Short, Harvey, 1963
    - Simpson, Howard R., 1961
    - Sinclair, T. L., 1961-1963
    - Smart, Jacob E., 1960 (Box 41)
    - Smith, Stephen, 1961
    - Soliman, Marcos, 1963
    - Sorenson, Nancy, 1963
    - Spaeth, Carl B., 1962
    - Splain, Colonel John F., 1960
    - Spore, Burns W., 1961-1962
    - Spruance, Raymond A., 1957
    - Stein, Leonard, 1961
    - Stewart, C. Allan, 1963
    - Stilwell, Richard G., 1963
    - Stone, I. F., 1964
    - Stoneman, Walter, 1962-1963
    - Strausz-Hupe, Robert, 1962
    - Stuart, Gilbert, 1961
    - Stump, Felix B., 1960
    - Stuntz, Mayo S., 1956
    - Stutesman, John, 1963
    - Suter, Dwayne, 1962
    - Sycip, Albino Z., 1957, 1960
    - Talbot, Bert J., 1957-1958
    - Tanham, George K., 1962-1963
    - Tausch, Roland D., 1963
    - Taylor, George E., 1962
    - Taylor, Maxwell D., 1963
    - Taylor, Robert, III, 1963
    - Taylor, Robert P., 1963
    - Taylor, Rufus L., 1963
    - Te Quang Tung, 1960
    - Thai, Nguyen [see: Nguyen Thai]
    - Thayer, Charles W., 1963
    - Thomas, Jack E., 1961
    - Thuan (unidentified), 1960
    - Tung, Te Quang [see: Te Quang Tung]
    - Tinio, Joe, 1958-1963
    - Toland, John, 1960
    - Townsend, E. C., 1963
    - Tran Van Chuong, 1964
    - Tran Van Dinh, 1962
    - Trinh Hung Ngau, 1963
    - Trinidad, Lina and Koko, 1960
    - Tudor, William L., 1961
    - Tull, James N., 1959
    - Ty, Le Van [see: Le Van Ty]
    - United States Department of State, Agency for International Development, 1962
    - United States Naval Institute Proceedings, 1963
    - Valencia, A. L., 1961
    - Valenzona, Ben S., 1962
    - Valeriano, Napolian D., 1957-1963
    - Van Thanh Cao, General, 1962-1963
    - Vance, Cyrus R., 1963
    - Vande Hey, James, 1963
    - Vanderbilt, William H., 1964
    - Volckmann, Russ W., 1963
    - Wachtel, Jack C., 1958-1961
    - Walsh, J. H., 1963
    - Ward, W. T. T., 1963
    - Warren, Robert H., 1963
    - Watson, Harold E., 1960
    - Westerfield, Bradford, 1963
    - White, Theodore H., 1962
    - Whitson, William W., 1963
    - Wieseman, F. L., 1965
    - Willems, 1961
    - Williams, "Doc,", 1963
    - Williams, Ogden, 1963
    - Williams, R. H., 1961
    - Williams, Samuel T., 1958-1963 (Box 42)
    - Williams, Stanley, 1964-1965
    - Williamson, T. Roney, 1963
    - Wilson, Brenda, 1962
    - Wilson, Delmar E., 1963
    - Wilson, John, 1963
    - Wilson, Samuel V., 1963
    - Wojtasiak, Major Frank J., 1962
    - Wolf, Charles, 1960-1963
    - Wooldridge, E. T., 1957
    - Xuan, Mai Huu [see: Mai Huu Xuan]
    - Yarborough, William P., 1961-1963
    - Yepez, Ceferina, 1962
    - Yoh, Bernard, 1958-1963
    - Yoh, Joan, 1962
    - Yone, E. M. Law, 1959
    - Young, Kenneth T., 1960-1961
    - Zander, Randolf, 1963
    - Zoller, Virgil L., 1962
    - Zuckert, the Hon. Eugene M., 1963
  - Memoranda
    - 1958-1961
    - 1962-1964
  - President's Committee to Study the United States Military Assistance Program (Draper Committee), Anderson Subcommittee
    - General
    - Miscellany
    - "American Military and Economic Aid in Asia," by Robert Blum, Asia Foundation, 1959 January 16
    - "An Appraisal of the Foreign Aid Program," by James R. Schlesinger, undated
    - Burma
    - Cambodia
    - "Central Question Before the Committee for Its Interim Report,", 1959 February 4
    - "Civic Activities of the Military, Southeast Asia," memorandum by Lansdale, 1959 March 13
    - Communications concerning Anderson group, 1954 January
    - Correspondence
      - Allen, George V., 1959 April
      - Anderson, Dillon, 1959 January-March
      - Bell, James D., 1959 March-April
      - Chuong, Tran Van [see: Tran Van Chuong]
      - Diem, President Ngo Dinh [see: Ngo Dinh Diem, President]
      - Fishel, Wesley R., 1959 February-April
      - Gailey, C. K., 1959 March
      - Kreidberg, M. A., 1959 March
      - Newton, Henry C., 1959 April
      - Ngo Dinh Diem, President [see also: Correspondence/Ngo Dinh Diem, President], 1959 January-April
      - RAND Corporation, 1959 April
      - Ravenholt, Albert and Marjorie, 1959 March
      - Reader's Digest (William J. Lederer), 1958-1959
      - Robertson, Walter, 1959 March
      - Sharpe, Laurence, 1959 April
      - Tran Van Chuong [see also: Correspondence/Tran Van Chuong], 1959 May
      - Wagonhurst, A. H., 1959 April
      - Wood, C. Tyler, 1959 April
    - Debriefing on Southeast Asia, memorandum for Mr. Irwin, 1959 March 24
    - "General Framework for Analysis of U.S. Programs of Military Assistance," by Robert Bowie and Lincoln Gordon, 1959 January 6
    - "India and China: Summary of Contrasts in Development Performance,", 1959 March 9
    - Indonesia
      - General
      - Conversation with Indonesian engineers, memorandum for the record, 1959 February 16 (Box 43)
    - Laos
    - Memorandum to the staff, 1959 February 9
    - Military advisors, 1963
    - Military assistance, memorandum for John Irwin, 1959 March 20
    - Military Assistance Program, memorandum for all Department of Defense and service speakers, 1959 March 23
    - Military assistance programming and budget review
    - "A National Staff to Plan the Cold War," by Richard H. Stephens, 1959 July 6
    - "Partial Analysis of Tasks of Area Study Teams," memorandum for the record, 1959 January 6
    - People visited, 1959 January 23-February 24
    - Peru, preliminary proposal of the delegation of Peru, 1958 November 17
    - Philippines
      - General
      - Economic Development Corps, Office of the Secretary of National Defense (Philippines), Report of the Chief, 1958 July 1-December 31
      - The Economic Development Corps (EDCOR) plan
    - "Population Explosion," by R. R. Adams, 1959 June 15
    - "The Scope of Future U.S. Actions Abroad," memorandum for the record, 1959 January 26
    - Southeast Asia
      - General
      - Briefings, 1959 March
      - "Highlights of Findings on Southeast Asia," by Lansdale, 1959 March 5
      - Trip, 1959 January 23-February 24
    - Southeast Asian countries visited, general characteristics
    - Thailand
    - "Thought Outline on the Development of Leadership Through MAP," by Lansdale, undated
    - "Training Under the Mutual Security Program," by R. G. Stilwell, 1959 May 15
    - Vietnam
  - Speeches and writings by Lansdale
    - Master file of classified talks
    - Miscellaneous (two folders), 1957-1961
    - Unpublished, notes, and miscellany
      - Two folders, 1960 (Box 44)
      - 1961
      - Three folders, 1962
      - 1963
    - "Binh Hung: A Counter-Guerrilla Case Study,", 1961 February 9 (Box 45)
    - "Civic Action," lecture, Counter-Guerrilla School, Fort Bragg, 1961 February 24
    - "Civic Action and Counter-Insurgency," memorandum, 1962 March 22
    - "Civil Activities of the Military, Southeast Asia," memorandum, 1959 March 13
    - "Counter-Guerrilla Operations in the Philippines, 1946-53," seminar, Fort Bragg, 1961 June 15
    - "Defense Activities in the Cold War," lecture, Army War College, 1960 December 21
    - "The Free Citizen in Uniform," talk, U.S. Army Civil Affairs School, Fort Gordon, Georgia, 1960 November 1
    - "Fundamentals for Americans," panel talk, Military Government Association, Washington, D.C., 1959 June 13
    - "The Insurgent Battlefield," talk, Air Force Academy, 1962 May 25
    - "Lessons Learned--The Philippines, 1946-53," lecture, Foreign Service Institute, Washington, D.C., 1962 September 26
    - "Letter From the Boon-Docks," memorandum, 1961 May 1
    - "Military Psychological Operations," lecture, Armed Forces Staff College, Norfolk, Virginia, 1960 January 7
    - "Partisan Warfare," memorandum, 1961 March 22
    - "Psychological Action by Air," memorandum, 1963 June 7
    - "A Roman General's Opinion of Military Critics,", undated
    - "Soldiers and the People," lecture, Fort Bragg, 1962 August 30
    - "Southeast Asia," lecture, Army War College, 1958 December 3
    - "Through Foreign Eyes," memorandum, 1963 October 7
    - "The True American,", 1960 June 3
    - "Unconventional Forces," lecture, Air War College, 1961 March 3
    - "The U.S. Military in Non-Military Warfare," panel, National War College, 1959 July 23
  - Subject file
    - Africa, "Leadership Training in Africa,", 1960 August 25
    - Air Force Reserve Officers Training Corps, visit by Lansdale, 1963 May 20
    - "Alert No. 6A: Lessons Learned from the Philippines, 1946-53," Washington, D.C.: Secretary of Defense, 1962
    - "Anti-Guerrilla Training in the Philippines," memorandum, 1956 January 17
    - Biographical sketches
    - Blair, Leon
    - Bolivia
      - General
      - Civic action, 1963 October
      - Trip to, 1963 May
    - Borneo, 1963
    - Burma
    - Carlisle Barracks and West Point, 1958-1959 (Box 46)
    - Chiang Ching-Kuo, General, visit with Lansdale, 1963 September 11
    - Clifford, John W.
    - Cold War, 1963
    - Colombia, 1963
    - Communist Organization for Unconventional Warfare, 1961
    - Congressional correspondence and testimony, 1962-1963
    - Counter-guerrilla operations, 1958-1960
    - Counter insurgency
    - Critical areas
    - Defense intelligence collection guide, 1963
    - Defense resources and programs for unconventional warfare, 1961
    - "Democracy by Cases," memorandum for Walt Rostow, 1963 February 6
    - "DOD Cold War Intelligence Requirements--For a Contested Free World Country,", 1958 June 9
    - Deutch, Michael J., memorandum to H. Sonnenfeldt on trip to Belgrade, undated
    - Dictionary of United States Military Terms for Joint Usage, Washington, D.C.: Joint Chiefs of Staff, 1959
    - Ecuador, 1963
    - Fishel, Wesley R. [see also: Correspondence/Fishel, Wesley R.]
    - Foreign Service Institute
    - Freedom, Incorporated
    - Haiti, military resources, 1963
    - "International Communist Front Organizations,", 1959 November
    - Iran, 1963
    - Israel, 1961
    - Killen, "Reorganization of the Office of Provincial Operations," memorandum, 1965 January 14
    - Kiraly, Major General Bela K.
    - Lansdale, Edward G. (Box 47)
    - Leave for Lansdale, memorandum for McNamara and Gilpatrick, 1962 November
      - Personal file
      - Requests for articles and reviews
      - Speaking requests
        - 1961 October - 1962 December
        - 1963
      - Travel file, 1961-1963
    - Laos
      - 1961-1963
      - Communist tactics in, 1960
    - Lasher, Major General E. C. R., "From Saratoga to Outer Space," New York: Newcomen Society, 1962
    - Latin America
      - 1963
      - Political Action Ideas, 1963 June 18